This forest is also known as the Darkness of Llinger.
那森林的别名叫"林格尔的黑暗"
It's famous for teeming with monsters.
是以魔物横行出名的地方
You're not coming home until you kill a Grand Grizzly.
没在这里抓到大灰熊之前
What?! W-wait a minute!
等一下等一下
N-no! Please stop! Don't pick me up!
不, 住手, 别把我提起来
Don't throw me, either!
不要一下子举那么高
This is bad! This is bad! This is bad!
惨了惨了惨了
I'm gonna die!
再这样下去我会死掉
Cause of death: Thrown by the Rescue Squad Captain!
(悲哀!! 部下被…)(嫌疑人 罗丝) 死因是救命团团长把部下丢出去
This isn't funny!
这真不是闹着玩的
I'm not going to die here!
怎么能死在这啊
I'm alive!
我还活着…太好了
But now that I've entered the forest,
就这样被丢进森林
I guess I've gotta do what Rose says if I want to go home.
虽然很不爽
A-all right! Kill a Grand Grizzly it is!
好, 就去打倒大灰熊吧
I mean, it's only a two-meter tall bear.
也不过是只约莫两公尺高的熊
That's nothing for someone who survived hell--
对于撑过地狱的我根本不算…
No way!
不会吧
The walls that tower over you
矗立的墙壁 虽然高耸厚实
They're not there to overwhelm you.
但这并非是为了放弃
They're there for you to overcome.
而是为了克服才存在
That's what I believe.
我如此相信着
For thousands of nights
于千万日夜中持续挑战
without losing my way.
眼光始终不移
As long as I can arrive
若能抵达最终章
it's okay even if
留下伤痕也无妨
Stand! Up! Again!
再次站起来
Over and over!
无论多少次
Don't! Look! Back!
不要回头看
Only towards the future.
只管朝着未来前进
(#3 Ruthless! The Darkness of Llinger!)
(#3 严酷! 林格尔的黑暗!)
It's coming after me!
追过来了!
It's far bigger than I thought!
话说它比我想的还大!
It's teeth and claws are hella huge!
牙齿和爪子都超级大!
But!
但是
I know I can outrun it!
我对脚程很有自信
No bear's gonna catch me!
区区的熊还想跟上我的速度
It's right behind me!
跟上来啦
Hold on! Think this through.
不, 仔细想想
I've managed to make it through that hellish training.
我可是一直在接受地狱的训练
This guy's nothing compared to Rose!
跟罗丝比起来, 这家伙算什么
Come at me, bear!
好啊, 你这臭熊
If it's a one-on-one fight--
就来单挑吧
That's cheating!
数量居然增加了, 太卑鄙了!
No one told me there'd be Blue Grizzlies, too!
我可没听说蓝灰熊会出现啊
This sound!
这声音是…
That was horrible.
真是惨透了
Some rations, a canteen, and a knife.
干粮, 水壶还有小刀吗
You could have at least given me something to start a fire with.
至少给我生火器具吧
Rose...
罗丝那家伙, 是恶鬼吗
Nah, she's more of an ogre.
不, 应该说她是食人魔才对
Kill a Grand Grizzly?
目标是讨伐大灰熊
No way that's gonna happen.
但我完全不觉得自己能办得到
Oh, well... I'll figure out what to do tomorrow.
算了, 明天再想想该怎么办吧
That's the end of Day One.
总之第一天结束了
Okay, let's do this.
好, 走吧
First thing's first.
不管怎样都得先了解对手才行
Let's figure out where it lives.
去找大灰熊的栖息地吧
Claw marks?!
磨爪的痕迹
Are those the Grand Grizzly's?
很有可能是那家伙
Could it be nearby?
它该不会就在附近吧
A rabbit?
兔子, 不, 是长得像兔子的魔物啊
Are you hurt?
你受伤了吗
It understands me?
它能听懂我说的话
Nah, can't be.
应该没这回事吧
Let me take a look at that.
让我看看
I healed it for you.
治好了
Don't get hurt again, okay?
别再受伤了喔
Don't follow me!
不要跟着我
I'm trying to find a scary monster!
我现在在找可怕魔物的栖息地
It's dangerous to be with me!
跟我在一起很危险的
I said no!
我都叫你别跟来了
...or do you happen to know where the Grand Grizzly is?
还是你知道大灰熊的栖息地在哪吗
You're kidding!
真的知道吗
It wasn't kidding!
真的在这里
That must be its den.
这洞穴就是那家伙的巢啊
Right, now to observe it without being spotted.
好
They look like a family.
它们好像是亲子
The book said that Grand Grizzlies live in groups.
书上有写大灰熊是群体生活的
I guess this counts?
这也算是一种群体吗
I don't think it's a good idea to drink untreated water...
虽然喝没煮沸的水有点不安
but I've got no choice.
没办法了
You're back again?
又跑回来了吗
You're a strange one, aren't you?
真是个奇怪的家伙
We're just looking today, okay?
今天也只有观察而已喔
No significant changes.
目前没有异状
The Blue Grizzlies are starting to look kinda cute.
蓝灰熊也越看越可爱了
This black rabbit is also really cute...
这黑兔子也超可爱
I'm having more fun than I thought...
总觉得出乎意料地幸福啊
My stomach hurts!
肚子好痛
I knew I shouldn't have drunk the river water!
果然是水的问题吗
Healing magic doesn't make it better...
使用治愈魔法也没办法马上治好
It's the same as being poisoned, after all.
毕竟这就跟被下毒没两样嘛
Still, there's got to be a way to cure it.
不过, 应该有治好拉肚子的方法才对
It's you! Back again?
你又来啦
All the same, I'm glad to see you!
不过你来看我, 我很开心喔
So, the water here's fine?
你的意思是这里的水可以喝吗
It certainly looks cleaner than the river water.
确实, 水看起来比河水干净
It's good! Thank you...
真好喝, 谢谢
Hey, what is it?
你怎么了
Does it sense a monster approaching?
有什么魔物到这附近了
But this guy didn't bat an eye at the Grand Grizzly.
可是它见到大灰熊都没这么害怕
What is that?
那是什么鬼啊
There wasn't anything in the book about that!
书上可没记载那种家伙的资料
But even I can tell...
不过, 有一点我很清楚
That thing's bad news.
那家伙很危险
There's nothing but bloodlust coming from it.
全身上下只感受得到杀气
I must never go near it... no matter what!
绝对不能靠近它
It's been four days since I saw that giant snake monster.
看到大蛇怪物后又过了四天
My uneasiness wouldn't let up,
不知为何心中的不安迟迟无法平息
and I just kept observing the Grizzlies.
不过我每天还是专注地观察大灰熊它们
These guys are the same as always.
它们还是老样子
Looking at them calms me down.
看了就觉得温馨
But if I don't kill that Grand Grizzly, I can't go home.
但我得打倒那只大灰熊才能回去
I have to do it.
只能动手了
Tomorrow.
明天就去挑战它吧
W-what is it?
怎么, 你叫我别去吗
But I have to...
就算你这么说…
Oh, very well.
好吧, 雨停前我就待在这里
Deal?
这样好吗
All right!
好
Here I come, Grand Grizzly!
给我等着瞧, 大灰熊
I'll make mincemeat out of you!
我要把你痛打一顿
There's no use stopping me.
你再怎么阻止我都没用
I'm going to kill it and get out of this forest.
我要打倒那家伙, 离开这座森林
Here goes nothing!
好
This is bad.
这下糟了
Rose is gonna kill me...
要是被罗丝知道我的猎物被抢了
if she finds out that something beat me to it.
我会被她宰掉的
Those bite marks.
这咬痕
It must have have been that big snake.
肯定是那大蛇干的
But it didn't kill them for food.
但是, 它不是为了进食才杀死它们
It killed them for fun.
而是出于好玩
It killed them just for the sake of it.
出于单纯的杀戮而动手
I hate losing.
我很不服输
That's why I didn't want to admit defeat to Rose.
所以我不甘心输给罗丝
That's why I hate having my prey stolen from me...
我的猎物被夺走
and having my resolve be for nothing.
让我的决心成了泡影也让我很不快
But above all...
但比这更重要的
I hate what I'm seeing right in front of me.
是我对眼前的景象感到非常不爽
I will avenge you.
我去帮你报仇
Just you wait.
所以在这等着吧
Training in the forest?
在森林修行?
You betcha. He's been gone for ten days.
是啊
Ten whole days? Isn't that a little long?
十天…也太久了吧
It's what Big Sis Rose decided... right?
这修行是罗丝大姐决定的, 对吧
S-she ain't around at the moment.
罗丝大姐不在, 我们也无能为力
Kazuki-kun, you get all fired up when it's about Usato-kun.
一树只要碰到兔里的事就会格外认真呢
I mean... aren't you worried, Senpai?
可是, 学姐你都不担心吗
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't worried...
说不担心是骗人的
But it's Rose-san we're talking about.
但既然是那个罗丝小姐要他做的
He'll be fine.
那就应该没问题吧
I wonder...
是这样吗
Besides, I believe in Usato-kun.
而且…
He'll come back in one piece.
他一定会平安回来
Hey...! I believe in him, too.
我也是…
Ready!
好了, 能带我去那条蛇那边吗
Just show me where it is.
只要带我去就好
You don't have to stay.
你之后就赶快跑
I... told you to wait!
那家伙我不是叫它等着吗
That thing really is dangerous! I'm scared!
那条蛇果然很危险
But...
不过…
there's nothing scarier than Rose!
哪有比罗丝可怕的家伙
It's confused! Time to strike!
它犹豫了, 好机会
That was close!
好险, 不过现在正是机会
Have an eyeful of this, you stupid snake!
吃我这招, 蠢蛇
That's all you've got?
就这种程度啊
Didn't feel a thing!
完全不痛不痒
I need to aim for its blind spot.
目标是那家伙的右侧死角
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
好痛…
It purposely lured me into its blind spot!
这家伙是故意让我跑到死角
And I fell for it!
上当了
But...
可是…
I have a knife in my hand!
我这只手拿着刀
Poison?!
有毒
On top of its big size? That's just not fair!
这种庞然大物居然有毒, 太卑鄙了
But I now know how to cure it.
但是, 我知道怎么治
I figured it out from when I got that stomachache.
拉肚子时我领会到了
If I'm being eaten away from the inside,
既然毒性会对体内造成损伤
all I've gotta do is to heal myself from the inside!
那只要从那里开始治疗就好
What are you...
你…
Got it!
我知道了
Did you think that was enough to get rid of me?
你以为这样就能把我甩下去吗
What are you,
你还真蠢啊
This is... the end!
这样就结束了
Go to hell!
去死吧
I did it!
太好了
I managed to avenge you.
我帮你报仇了
I'd love to heal your wounds,
虽然很想帮你疗伤
but I used up most of magic to cure the poison.
但看来治疗中毒让我几乎把魔力用完了
I can't even move...
我已经动不了了
You're kidding...
真的假的
Stop it! Run!
别管我, 快逃
Is this it?
到此为止了吗
Kazuki? Inukami-senpai? Rose?
一树, 犬上学姐, 罗丝
That's right! This is all Rose's fault!
没错, 一切都是罗丝害的
Damn it, Rose! You beast! You brute! You ogre!
可恶, 鬼畜罗丝, 暴力女
Come on...
真是的, 肮脏的臭蛇
All you had to do was die.
乖乖死掉不就得了
R-Rose-sama!
罗…罗丝大人
How are you here?
话说你怎么知道的
It's all thanks to this guy.
是这家伙通知我的
This is my pet, Kukuru. I sent it to watch over you.
(得意) 它是我的宠物库库勒
But it was hurt when we first met!
但那只兔子…是受着伤出现的
Still haven't figured it out?
真是迟钝
I had it put on an act to gain your trust.
为了取得你的信赖
No way!
骗人
I've been waiting at the edge of the forest
为了预防你遇到什么万一
just in case anything happened.
我一直都守在森林外面
I wasn't going to interfere, but I never expected this thing to appear.
虽然我原本想尽量袖手旁观
You recognize it?
所以你知道它吗
It's a monster modified by the Demon Lord's Army.
它是魔王军改造的魔物
During the last invasion, Siglis failed to finish it off.
没想到上次侵略时席古勒斯没杀掉它
This is where it must have run off to.
它应该是那之后逃到这里的吧
Still, to think it managed to kill a Grand Grizzly.
但真没想到大灰熊会被它杀死呢
Even our kingdom's elite forces won't be able to beat a Grand Grizzly unscathed.
那可是召集本国的精锐部队
You knew that and still pit me against one?!
你明知这点
You heartless demon!
你这魔鬼, 毫无人性!
I never expected you to win.
我本来就不认为你会赢
I just wanted you to gain experience fighting a stronger opponent.
我是要让你跟高手对战, 累积战斗经验
But then...
但是…
But then?
但是?
Things started to get interesting.
你却出乎我意料地有趣
I wanted to see what would happen, so I let you continue.
我好奇接下来的发展, 就让你继续了
I almost died, you know?!
我可是差点就要死了耶
He's taken a liking to you, I see.
它喜欢上你了吗
H-he has?
是这样吗
Now that I think about it, he has lost his parents...
这么说来, 它失去了双亲
He's all alone.
变得孤零零的啊
I knew you were a man after my own heart.
你果然跟我很像
Hey, Blue Grizzly!
蓝灰熊
You're coming with us!
我要带你一起走
Carry that walking corpse.
把这半死不活的废物背起来
You're letting me ride you?
你好像愿意跟着走, 真的可以吗
Now, then. Let's go home.
好了, 回去吧
Please, no. She scares me.
我受够了, 这人好恐怖
That reminds me... what did you call me just now?
话说, 你刚刚叫我什么?
A beast? A brute? An ogre?
鬼畜, 暴力女, 食人魔?
You're not getting any sleep tonight!
你今晚别想睡觉了
Y-yes ma'am!
是
with flying colors.
你甚至超越了合格的水准
You have earned the right.
你今天起已经有资格了
The right?
什么资格?
The right to stand by my side on the battlefield.
跟我一起站上战场的资格
You still lack training...
虽然基础还不够, 但你有这些特质
A body that can withstand pain, the physical prowess, and...
禁得起痛苦的肉体, 体能
an indomitable spirit.
强韧的精神力
All the things the other two healers lack.
这是其他两位治愈魔法使没有的东西
Be proud.
以此自豪吧
We might still make it in time.
照这状况, 说不定来得及
In time for what?
什么意思?
The Demon Lord's Army will make its move soon.
魔王军…马上要来了
Third Army Commander Amila Vergrett.
第三军团长, 艾蜜拉．贝尔古雷
Milord.
在
How is the Llinger Kingdom invasion coming along?
入侵林格尔王国的状况如何了
It is all going according to plan.
非常顺利
All our units are preparing for battle.
现在部队逐渐准备就绪
We will soon be able to advance.
很快就能出兵
The beginning was sudden and silent.
开端是如此无声无息突如其来
Then, everything before me began to change.
眼中所见的所有风景都在改变
Even the stones lying at my feet
即便是脚边滚动的石子
seem to shine a little brighter.
亦不知为何都有些闪耀
That's because you're reflected in them.
或许是因为每次相见时
Like a young leaf that's just sprouted,
仿佛才刚发芽的嫩叶般
Let the wind blow you onward.
微风吹拂 毫不迷惘地前进吧
If I'm with you, I can go anywhere.
只要与你一起
Even if you're not special, you can be anything.
即便并不特别
Let me believe in the strength that's awakened in your heart.
让我相信那心中觉醒的坚强